Wayne D. Bloss

Summary

Senior developer and manager with 15+ years experience developing web, desktop and mobile applications. My areas of expertise are in ASP.NET, C#, JavaScript, SQL Server and VB which I learned growing up. Within the JavaScript world I have experience with Angular.js, Express.js, jQuery, Node.js, and React/Redux. Have experience managing small teams and large projects.

Experience

May 2016 - Jan. 2018

National Field Network, Inc.

Howell, NJ

Software Developer

- Designed and built a CRM and form-builder for tracking sub-contractor field-worker tasks using C#, ASP.NET Web API, SQL Server and Angular.
- Created an privately-deployed mobile app for iOS and Android using Angular and Ionic/Cordova for field workers to fill out forms and submit proof of work via photos and GPS coordinates.
- Setup project management and developer operations workflow tools for all projects.

June 2014 – Mar. 2016

Jersey Central Management, Inc.

Lakewood, NJ

Software Developer

- Created a CRM-style trust-fund management system with Knockout, Bootstrap, jQuery, ASP.NET Web API and SQL Server 2012.
- Built a high-speed check-printing system with iTextSharp and an open source MICR font.
- Maintenance programming for the companys property management CRM systems built with ASP.NET and SQL Server.

Aug 2012 – April 2014

Direct Success, Inc.

Wall, NJ

Software Developer

- Primary developer tasked with building Specialty Pharmacy infrastructure and reporting systems.
- Integrated CPR+ pharmacy CRM software with the company's High Volume Fulfillment application using SQL Server 2008 R2, SQL Server 2005, ASP.NET, C# and .NET 4.0.
- Designed and implemented a data driven system for producing combined Shipping and Prescription labels for fulfillment using C#, WinForms, iTextSharp and the UPS Shipping API.
- Created an ad-hoc Excel template and reporting system used by the majority of the company staff to access reports. Technologies used: C#, WinForms, T4, EPPlus, SOL Server 2012.
- Created over 125 reports for pharmacy sales, data entry, patient tracking, inventory, fulfillment, auditing and other operations.
- Built a system for other IT users to analyze and work through sets of bugs scraped from a large client's web-based bug tracking system.
- Designed and implemented a number of utility programs for internal operations including a prescription validation tool, a tool to automate Windows Remote Support for the IT staff, a utility to get or assign a special group membership for new patients and various other tools and web services for data import, export and validation.
- All software implemented to follow HIPAA, SOX and PCI standards.

April 2012 – Aug 2012

Clear Computing, Inc.

Tinton Falls, NJ

Software Developer

- Maintenance programming for VB6, SQL Server and .NET application components.
- Troubleshooting and support for a niche CRM desktop program.
- Dealing with domestic and international clientele.

Aug 2002 – May 2011

Dial Connection, LLC

Berlin, NJ

Software Developer

- Created an ASP.NET web portal to convert VOX audio files to MP3 on demand and stream the resulting audio to customers via Flash and optionally, Microsoft Media Services.
- Built a real-time telephony dialer monitoring service and desktop application with C#, WCF, Linq to SQL, WinForms and DevExpress components.
- Developed the company's first dedicated reporting package including a large number of the actual reports using Crystal Reports, ASP and VB6 (this was back in 2002-2003).
- Built an Interactive Voice Response (IVR) service with C#, WCF and a host of proprietary telephony related components.
- Ported a C++ Winsock client/COM project to C# and expanded the feature set to allow asynchronous operation for each of the few hundred or so API calls.
- Maintenance programming on numerous and varied VB6 applications.
- Developed stored procedures, scripts, integration packages and deployment plans for SQL Server (2000 – 2008).
- Managed a critical project to develop the company's first in-house telephony service (C++) which allowed them to switch away from an old, buggy and proprietary telephony package. Co-wrote unit tests to test the new product during development.
- Managed many small projects and trained new developers.

More Experience

Please ask about my prior experience. I have a fairly long history of work in the field of computer technology and I have been programming computers since learning BASIC at a young age.

Education

1988 – 1992	Toms River High School North	Toms River, NJ
1994 – 1996	Ocean County College	Toms River, NJ